Tucson Commission on Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Transgendered Issues Collection 1999-2009
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Tucson Commission on Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Transgendered Issues Collection 1999-2009
MS 501
Tucson Commission on Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Issues
This collection is comprised of documents generated and compiled by the Tucson GLBT commission from its inception in 1999. The bulk of the material are meeting notes from monthly meetings, but also includes specific research into the commission’s area of interest such as hate crimes, transgender awareness and domestic partnerships. While the material is mostly documents, there are some AV materials that are designed as outreach for the community. It also contains community feedback and criticism regarding GLBT topics.
4.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Originated in 1998 as a mayoral task force in response to a hate crime in Tucson, the force evolved into a Commission of its own in 1999. The commission deals with a number of GLBT-related issues in the community, including HIV awareness and advocating for the gay community.
The commission was charged with advocating for the GLBT community in the Tucson area. Under this sanction, they developed political and social policies to better the lives of those in this community, including the creation of sensitivity training for local employers/employees and Arizona’s first Domestic Partner Registration. Among its other accomplishments were the addition of gender identity to civil rights protections and a recommendation of standard practices for health care and social services.
A crucial part of Tucson history and of the push forward for GLBT rights in the Southwest, the Tucson Commission for Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender issues remains one of the few government sanctioned independent commissions for advocacy in the country.
Arrangement
This Collection is organized into 4 series.
Series I: Manuals Undated
Series II: Meetings October 1999- September 2009
Subseries 1: Correspondence
Subseries 2: Committee
Subseries 3: Subcommittee
Series III: Research 2000-2007
Series IV: Outreach Undated
Scope and Content Note
Documents, few AV materials and electronic files on disk storage 1999-2009. This collection is comprised of the meetings, correspondence and research of the Tucson Commission of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Transgendered Issues. The bulk of the material relates meeting agendas and information researched by subcommittees. The collection includes the meeting agendas and official notes taken at the monthly meetings. The Commission observed summer and winter recesses causing the lapse of a month or two in the notes. This collection contains research done by the commission in response to the issues involving the GLBT community such as Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell and HIV. Some outreach materials have been retained including, hate crime videos and the Don’t Play in the Park campaigns. Correspondence with leading politicians, such as the mayor and the fire chief, is also included.
Access Terms
Gay activists--United States
Sexual minorities--Civil rights--Arizona--Tucson
Domestic partner benefits--Law and legislation--Arizona
Hate crimes--Arizona
Container List
- Series I: Manuals Undated
  This series contains the different manuals and handbooks retained by the commission
  - GLBT Commission Handbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commission, Boards and Commission Handbooks, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commission Manual (1 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commission Manual (2 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Commission Manual (3 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II: Meetings October 1999- September 2009
  This series is arranged in chronological order. It contains meeting agendas, notes and related materials divided between correspondence, committee and subcommittee.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 2003-2006, 2008
    - Correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Committee, 1999-2009
    - Committee-Electronic Files on DVD and floppy disk, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Committee-Financial, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Committee, October 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Committee, November Interviews 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Committee, December Interviews 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, October 1999-December 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 1999-December 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2001-August 2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, September 2001-December 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2004, June 2004-September 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, March 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, April 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Meeting Notes, , May 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, October 2004-December 2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2005-May 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, July 2005-September 2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, October 2005-December 2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2006-September 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, October 2006-March 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, May 2007-September 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, May 2007-December 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2008-June 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, September 2009-December 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Committee-Meeting Notes, January 2009-September 2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3: Subcommittee, 1999-2008
    - Subcommittee on Education, 1999-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Subcommittee- on Legal, 1999-2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Subcommittee- on Park Sex, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Subcommittee- on Social Services, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series III: Research, February 2000-2007 Undated
  This series is subdivided by broad theme and then arranged chronologically. It contains research notes and community responses
  - Anti-Discrimination-Assorted Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts-Mayor Comment Line, February 20, 2000-September 24, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Boy Scouts-Mayor Comment Line, September 25, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Boy Scouts-Mayor Comment Line, September 26, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mayor Comment Line, September 27, 2000-October 2, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - United Way Correspondence, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell- Repeal, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Firefighters-Women’s Firefighting Assorted Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Firefighters-Firefighter Sensitivity Training Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Firefighters-Fire Department Related News Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Firefighters-Richard Miranda Hate Crime, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Firefighters-Opela Hate Crime (1of 2), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Firefighters- Opela Hate Crime (2of 2), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - HIV-Robert/Meeks Article and Correspondence, July 2005 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Transgender-Transgender News and Related Material, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Domestic Partnership-Assorted Materials and Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Domestic Partnership-Other States’ Policies, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Outreach Undated
  This series contains outreach materials used to educate the public
  - Notes and Information, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hate Crimes DVD and video, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)